Preliminary Guide to the Washington State University Facilities Planning Building Files 1983-1990
Washington State University Libraries Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections
Preliminary Guide to the Washington State University Facilities Planning Building Files
1983-1990
Washington State University Libraries, Manuscripts, Archives and Special Collections
UA1995-10
Washington State University. Facilities Planning
3 Linear feet of shelf space 3 Boxes
Estimated cost breakdowns and specs on updates to systems and WSU buildings, as well as general administrative information from the Facilities Planning department. Records cover 1983-1990.
The office of Facilities and Planning did not exist as a full-time staffed administrative department at WSU until 1947. Prior to this a University Architect served as the construction officer of WSU dating to 1911. Facilities and Planning awas later renamed as Facilities and Development. It is responsible for major construction projects on WSU campus.
Correspondence about various systems and WSU buildings, covering 1983-1990. Includes spec books from various expansions and remodels, and utility cost breakdowns for various buildings. Box 1 contains four spec books on the Holland Library expansion (later Terrell), and system reports for things on campus such as ventilation, snow melt system, infrared, greenhouses, and insulation. Box 2 contains administrative files on cost estimates and utility cost breakdowns for various buildings and fuel sources. Box 3 contains an estimate summary on the Holland Library addition.
This is an unprocessed collection. Any arrangement reflects either a pre-existing order from the records' creators or previous custodians, or preliminary sorting performed by staff.
Documents remain in their original order.
This collection is open and available for research use.
This material was transferred to WSU Libraries' MASC by Rick Ward of Facilities on June 15, 1995 and retained as UA1995-10.
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Washington State University. Facilities Planning -- Records and correspondence
Washington (State); Colleges and Universities
- Snow Melt System 1994 (Box 1)
- Roof Installation 1980 (Box 1)
- Steam Line Insulation - Specifications and Drawings 1984: French Administration Building (Box 1)
- Energy Conservation 1977: Greenhouses (Box 1)
- Steam and Condensate Projects 1979 (Box 1)
- Ventilation 1983: White Hall Basement (Box 1)
- Ventilation System 1984: Holland Library (Box 1)
- U.S. Corps of Engineers Specifications Book/Manuals 1986, Vols. I-IV (Box 1)
- Solar II: Steam Power 1978-1983 (Box 2)
- Compton Union Building Utility Costs (Box 2)
- Energy Office, WA State (Olympia), Frederick S. Adair, Acting Director (Box 2)
- Cogeneration (Box 2)
- Coal Ash Disposal (Box 2)
- Energy - Reports, Correspondence 1970 - 1987 (Box 2)
- Solar Energy (Box 2)
- Auxiliary Enterprises (Utilities Billing) (Box 2)
- Correspondence - Energy Street Lighting - Carrier Cost Analysis (Box 2)
- Cogeneration II and V (Box 2)
- Cogeneration III (Box 2)
- WA State Energy Office: Conservation Projects Annual Report 1983 (Box 2)
- Inner - Office Correspondence (Box 2)
- WA State Energy Office: Annual Energy Usage Rept. 1985 - 1987 BI (Box 2)
- Fuel - General (Box 2)
- Fuel - Coal Storage Areas (Box 2)
- Fuel Gas, Natural (Box 2)
- Fuel - Oil, Lubricants (Box 2)
- WA State Energy Office: Annual Energy Usage Rept. 1983 - 1985 BI (Box 2)
- Energy Conservation Management and Office and Maintenance Information (Box 2)
- Energy Management Report - Pullman Campus 1983 (Box 2)
- Campus Square Footage (Box 2)
- Miscellaneous (Box 2)
- Energy Audit - Walk Through Status Sheet - Pullman Campus (Box 2)
- New Electric Data - Campus Apartments (Box 2)
- Energy Conservation - Miscellaneous (Box 2)
- Energy Conservation - Miscellaneous (Box 2)
- WSU Building Roster - Compiled by Facilities Planning Office 1980's (Box 2)
- Energy Conservation - Small Projects, Letters (Box 2)
- Holland Library Addition - Morrison Knudson Estimate Summary - Concrete - May 1991 (Box 3)
- Holland Library Addition - Morrison Knudson Estimate Bid Book - May 3, 1991 (Box 3)
- Holland Library Addition - Morrison Knudson Estimate Summary - Mechanical - May 1991 (Box 3)